Pradeep G. Bhosale

FRONT-END DEVLOPER

https://pradeepbhosle8.github.io/pradeepbhosle/

90/665, Aijnkya Society, M.H.B. Colony, Dindoshi Nager Malad East, Mumbai -97. +91 9967544174

pradeep.bhosle8@gmail.com

https://github.com/pradeepbhosle8

Front End Developer with 5 plus years of experience in the Finance domain, e-commerce, and Society web application experience in mern stack hand code experience in Web and Mobile Applications development using technologies like HTML5, CSS3/SASS, JavaScript, React, RTK Query, Angular cli-13, Node, Express API, Git, Web Services. Expert knowledge of the UI design process and deliverables throughout the development lifecycle. Passionate about usability and possess working knowledge of Adobe Photoshop & Figma.

KEY SKILLS

HTML, CSS/SASS, JavaScript, React, RTK Query, Angular cli -13, Node, Express API, Gitlab, Git, Figma, Photoshop, Clear communication, Innovative problem-solving, Attention to detail, Highly organised.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Carnelian Payment Networks India Pvt Ltd.

Senior Front End Developer

27 September 2021 – Present

CPNI pvt ltd is a leading application like M society web app, Payment Gateway web app, POS inventory web app.

- M society (https://paynet.co.in/m-society/), Payment Gateway
 - Implementing web design and development principles to build stable software.
 - Bringing mock-ups to life using Anular-12.
 - Developing features to enhance the user experience.
 - Ensuring web design is optimized for smart phones.
 - Building, optimizing and maintaining front-end web apps.
 - Collaborating closely with the team to support projects during all phases of delivery.
 - Maintaining an organized work flow using a project management tool (like GitHub).
 - Testing to identify bugs and technical issues before and after deploying
 - Building websites and apps that are responsive and usable.

- Monitoring website performance and rectifying front-end-related issues
- o Implement node api from user registration module
- Maintaining an organized work flow using a project management tool (like GitHub).
- Adapting interface for modern internet applications using the latest frontend technologies

V'GROW Solutions Pvt Ltd.

Senior Front End Consultant

1st January 2020 – 27 September 2021.

Skills & Tools: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, React, Angular4+, Bootstrap, Gitlab.

- Implemented websites, mobile applications, and landing pages from concept through deployment.
- Building websites and apps that are responsive and usable.
- Testing to identify bugs and technical issues before and after deploying.
- Standardized all output with a new, responsive, mobile-first approach and strategy.
- Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments.
- Proficiency in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery.
- Coordinating the work flow between the graphic designer, the HTML coder, and yourself
- Maintaining an organized work flow using a project management tool (like Git Hub).
- Testing to identify bugs and technical issues before and after deploying

FREELANCER

Front End Developer

20 September 2016 – 25 December 2020

- Bringing mock-ups to life using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Assisted other developers in updating and extending code for e-commerce websites.
- Worked as part of the team on projects, and received regular guidance.
- Worked closely with team members to create consistent, reusable, and maintainable code. designed new software systems or updates to existing systems.
- Coordinated and participated in implementation testing and support
- Provided timely turnaround and documentation of bug fixes during the test cycle.
- Testing to identify bugs and technical issues before and after deploying.

• Implementing web design and development principles to build stable software

Craftsvilla.com pvt ltd

Web Designer and Developer

1 September 2015 – 9 September 2016

Skills & Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Word Press, Angular, Git

- Worked with the team, helping them build out their markup and CSS. My specialty is large scale HTML, CSS, focusing on re usability and modularity.
- Creating new Features, Functionality and capabilities on the eCommerce site using Ajax, fetch, JSON and Angular.
- Creating Modular, Responsive landing page using SASS, CSS, HTML and jQuery.
- Fixed bugs from existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved web functionality and speed
- Built and implemented custom templates for Mehndi blog in WordPress.

Unotech Software pvt ltd

Front End Developer, UI Developer

22 July 2013 – 29 August 2015

Skills & Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jquery, JavaScript, Putty, PHP, WordPress

- Enhanced user experience and accomplish webpage objectives by creating site structure, navigation, page optimization integration.
- Designed and maintained both corporate and client websites, using scripting languages and content management systems including WordPress.
- Client project handle like. Klip.in, BSE scanning doc. Mahindra finance and insurance, PMA, Stepathlon social network, Transpure Pvt ltd etc.

Robocom pvt ltd

Junior Web Designer, Graphic Designer

18 November 2010 – 4 June 2012

- Developed websites from scratch
- Creating Static site structure, navigation, page optimization, and integration.
- Cooperation with team members Implemented enhancements that improved web functionality and responsiveness.

EDUCATION

Mumbai University

Diploma in Graphics and Web Designing

Bachelor of Science in Botany, May 2009

2010